# MICHAEL QUIBUYEN WEB DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER

## **SUMMARY**

It's my goal to work collaboratively with people who have a desire to create or develop new technology that strive toward solving complex problems. I have a passion for designing beautiful user experiences (UX) for the web and mobile apps.



QUIBUYEN.MICHAEL@GMAIL.COM



(714) 342-7782



HTTP://MICHAELQUIBUYEN.COM

# **WORK EXPERIENCE POPPIR**

## **Graphic Designer**

September 2016 - Present

- Created optimized web images for internal marketing materials, presentations, social media posts, as well as online blog stories.
- Managed graphic design requests from the web development, marketing, and business development teams as well as developed consistent branding across all disciplines.
- Researched, assisted and presented new ideas for creative marketing campaigns.
- Altered graphic elements or photographs as needed to deliver high quality images.

#### WEB DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER

Freelance

February 2016 - Present

- Managed client work from local and online freelance sources such as Upwork and Fiverr focused on web development and design.
- Responsible for the graphic design and implementation of client websites, including writing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript as well as optimization of web graphics.
- Performed validation of completed sites including the debugging and testing of code.
- Ensured all web site development follows W3C web standards and ADA compliance for accessibility and other good practices for web design and development.

#### U.S. HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, CONGRESSWOMAN JULIA BROWNLEY (CA-26)

Staff Assistant

February 2015 - Present

- Assisted the press team with drafting posts to share on Facebook and Twitter, drafting mass e-newsletter or e-mails via our CRM, designed graphics to be used in marketing materials or mail pieces, professional photography of the Congresswoman, maintained and added content to our Drupal website, and collected press clips for the office.

### **BLOC**

## User Experience (UX) Design Apprenticeship

February 2015 - November 2015

- Collaborated remotely with a professional design mentor to develop my process and techniques as a UX designer.
- Produced UX deliverables including user stories, personas, user flows, wireframes, mockups, as well as created original branding and visual identities for concepts throughout project tasks to meet product and user needs.
- Built and tested live prototypes for a fundraising platform, iOS App, and SaaS landing page using front-end code.

#### CALIFORNIA STATE ASSEMBLY, ASSEMBLYMEMBER SHARON QUIRK-SILVA (CA-65)

#### Field Represenative / Press Assistant

March 2013 - December 2014

- Worked on projects including graphic design for program advertisements at various events, communications work drafting press releases, political photography and videography at events, and case management to assist constituents with State agencies.

## **EDUCATION**

Code School Paths: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and the MEAN Stack Self-Paced Online Learning (Feb. 2016 to Present)

California State University, Long Beach B.S. Environmental Science and Policy; Political Science Minor (Dec. 2012)



Congressional Asian Pacific American

Staff Association (CAPASA)

MEMBER:

American Istitute of Graphic

Arts (AIGA), Washington, DC Chapter



USER RESEARCH

skills

**USABILITY TESTING** 

**PERSONAS** 

**USER FLOWS** 

ULDESIGN

**CONTENT STRATEGY** 

INTERACTION DESIGN

HTML/CSS/JAVASCRIPT

PHOTOGRAPHY

tools

**PHOTOSHOP** 

**ILLUSTRATOR** 

**SKETCH** 

BALSAMIO

INVISION

GIT/GITHUB

CODA

MICROSOFT OFFICE SUITE

community

COMMUNICATIONS CHAIR:

